## **Donald Richardson**

#### Expert leadership in modern technology systems

503-784-6641 @ me@donaldrichardson.net ∂ www.linkedin.com/in/donald-g-richardson/

Technical leader with over 20+ years of industry experience and 7+ years of leadership experience. Dedicated to the craft of the art of the possible, combining critical business thinking, empathetic communication, and deep technical expertise. Committed to being a foundational partner and teammember in a growth-driven, forward-thinking company.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Platform Technology Director

Gensler 10/2021 - 03/2023 New York, New York - Remote

- Responsible for technical research, synthesis and analysis for core software product
- Represented technical expertise for short-, mid-, and long-term business goals and product go-to-market strategy
- Established software development standards, technology ecosystem, and pipeline from the ground-up to build a new team and capability within the company
- Defined and documented a robust software development lifecycle (SDLC)
- Detailed definition of system architecture and delineation of product requirements and user stories
- Responsible for security, privacy, and compliance requirements

#### Creative Technology Director, New York Studio

Gensler 07/2018 - 10/2021 New York, New York

- · Responsible for managing the technical aspects of digital experience projects from inception to production to sustainment
- Responsible for technical project management including planning, budgeting, stakeholder communication, team building, and team management
- Responsible for software architecture, information architecture, data modeling, and the development of critical or high-touch components for project work
- Led or significantly contributed to dozens of projects, many for Fortune 500 clients, totalling in 35M+ of revenue
- Worked closely and created strategic partnerships with external parties and vendors
- Grew and mentored and team members

#### System Architect & Engineer

C&G Partners LLC 07/2017 - 07/2018 New York, New York

- System architecture for a large-scale project for a cultural institution in DC
- Establishment of information architecture & data model for over a dozen interactive experiences
- Implementation of backend including headless CMS content distribution functionality, 3rd party data aggregation, management & moderation of user generated content, and more
- Implementation of devops functionality including CI/CD, software deployment, & configuration management

#### Digital Experience Developer

Red Paper Heart 03/2017 - 07/2017 New York, New York

- Creation of a tennis swing tracking system for an interactive game for Samsung
- Web-based tablet experience for an interactive experience for an event sponsored by Ford Motors

#### **Technical Consultant**

Art Institute of Chicago 10/2016 - 03/2017 New York, New York - Remote

- Stakeholder research & requirements synthesis for website modernization
- In-depth technical audit of relevant internal systems
- Proposal of a modernized technical architecture to allow for better integration of components, better scalability & modularity
- Plan & documentation for implementation of modernized system

#### Technical Director, New York Studio

Second Story Interactive Studios 10/2015 - 10/2016 New York, New York

- . Put in place technical process, standard architecture, & coding conventions for software development throughout the lifetime of the project
- Established strategic relationships with vendors & partners
- Responsible for technical hiring & resourcing

#### Technical Lead

Second Story Interactive Studios 10/2013 - 10/2015 Portland, Oregon

. Managed the technical aspects of numerous industry-leading and award-winning projects on-budget and on-time

Management Skills

**Visioning & Alignment** 

**Stakeholder Communication** Agile / Lean

**Budgeting & Forecasting** 

**Team Building** 

**Testing** 

**Go-to-market Strategy** 

**Product Ownership & Management** 

**Project Management** 

**Process Definition & Standards** 

**Technical Skills** 

**System Architecture** 

**Documentation & Diagramming** 

**DevOps Pipeline** 

Cloud

**SDLC** 

Security/Privacy/Compliance

Infrastructure / IaC **Agile Development** 

**Software Development** 

**Hardware Specification** 

Front-end Web Technologies

Vite **Typescript ESNext** Webpack **HTML CSS** Sass/Less **Tailwind** 

React Redux Recoil SSR

Accessibility Security WebGL

Three.JS Electron

Other Front-end Technologies

**TouchDesigner** Cinder

**OpenFrameworks** OpenGL

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Full-stack Developer / Interactive Developer / Sr. Interactive Developer

Second Story Interactive Studios 08/2009 - 10/2013 Portland, Oregon

. Software architecture and development from backend and devops systems to web, mobile, desktop, and high-performance OpenGL applications

### Full-stack Developer

Full-time roles at multiple companies 2003 - 2009 Portland Oregon

- · Web application development
- · UI/UX feasibility analysis
- · Feature prioritization
- Bug fixes
- · Change management
- E-commerce
- · Prototyping

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Science, Mathematics

Portland State University 2000 - 2006 Portland, Oregon SKILLS

#### DevOps

DevOps
laC Terraform Pulumi
Configuration Management Puppet
SaltStack SCM Git Subversion
CI/CD Github Actions Observability
New Relic Feature Flags
Artifact Repository Nexus
Documentation C4 Atlassian
Back-end Technologies
Python C# C++ Typescript
Node.js Cloud Serverless AWS
SQL PostgresQL MySQL
Stored Procedures NoSQL MongoDB
REST Swagger GraphQL Apollo
Testing Jest Cypress.io Cucumber
Messaging RabbitMQ Django
Express/Koa Docker
AWS Technologies
Lambda EC2 S3 VPC API Gateway
Cloudfront DynamoDB AmazonMQ
SNS SQS Route53 Load Balancing
IAM Cognito
Other
IoT Arduino Raspberry PI

**Depth Sensors**